Privacy Policy of Blue Ocean Law Group

Blue Ocean Law Group collects some Personal Data from its Users.

Owner and Data Controller

James D. Ford

General Practice Lawyer | Founder \& M.D.

Blue Ocean Law Group

c/- Work Club Level 8, 99 Elizabeth Street

Sydney NSW 2000

Owner contact email: privacy@blueocean.law

Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that Blue Ocean Law Group collects, by itself or through third parties,

there are: first name; last name; phone number; company name; profession; physical address; fax number;

country; state; email address; ZIP/Postal code; various types of Data; city; field of activity; website; Trackers;

Usage Data; answers to questions; clicks; keypress events; motion sensor events; mouse movements; scroll

position; touch events; Data communicated while using the service; payment info; billing address; user

content; contents of the email or message; profile picture; date of the message; time the message was sent;

sender of the message.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this

privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.

Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when

using Blue Ocean Law Group.

Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by Blue Ocean Law Group is mandatory and failure to provide

this Data may make it impossible for Blue Ocean Law Group to provide its services. In cases where Blue

Ocean Law Group specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate

this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.

Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools — by Blue Ocean Law Group or by the owners of third-party

services used by Blue Ocean Law Group serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in

addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through Blue Ocean

Law Group.

Mode and place of processing the Data

Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or

unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational

procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the

Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of Blue Ocean Law

Group (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party

technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies)

appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be

requested from the Owner at any time.

Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in

the processing are located.

Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other

than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the

section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

Retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as

required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal

obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

The purposes of processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Service, comply with its legal

obligations, respond to enforcement requests, protect its rights and interests (or those of its Users or third

parties), detect any malicious or fraudulent activity, as well as the following: Contacting the User, User

database management, Spam and bots protection, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing),

Displaying content from external platforms, Handling payments, Managing contacts and sending messages,

Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Operations, Selling goods and services online,

Platform services and hosting, Tag Management, Traffic optimization and distribution, Hosting and backend

infrastructure, Registration and authentication, Content commenting, Handling activities related to

productivity, Infrastructure monitoring, Collection of privacy-related preferences, Analytics and Interaction

with live chat platforms.

For specific information about the Personal Data used for each purpose, the User may refer to the section

“Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data”.

Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used

to keep track of User behavior.

Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) with anonymized IP (Google LLC)

Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) is a web analysis service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google

utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of Blue Ocean Law Group, to prepare reports on its

activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users' IP addresses

within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the

European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server

and shortened within the US.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt Out.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Collection of privacy-related preferences

This type of service allows Blue Ocean Law Group to collect and store Users’ preferences related to the

collection, use, and processing of their personal information, as requested by the applicable privacy

legislation.

Finsweet Cookie Consent

Our Privacy Preference Center is provided via the Finsweet Cookie Consent Solution and delivered to our

website via the Content Delivery Network (CDN) JSDELIVR.

JSDELIVR is a free Content Delivery Network (CDN) for Open Source located in Poland (within the EU

therefore it operations are subject to the GDPR) designed, developed and maintained by Prospect One and

Dmiytu Akutov.

CDN's are used to enable faster website load times globally.

Fast, reliable, and automated.

Around since 2012.

Serving ~ 177 billion requests/month.

You can read their Privacy Policy here:

https://www.jsdelivr.com/terms/privacy-policy-jsdelivr-net

iubenda Consent Database (iubenda srl)

The iubenda Consent Database allows to store and retrieve records of Users’ consent to the processing of

Personal Data, and information and preferences expressed in relation to the provided consent.

In order to do so, it makes use of a Tracker that temporarily stores pending information on the User’s device

until it is processed by the API. The Tracker (a browser feature called localStorage) is at that point deleted.

Personal Data processed: Data communicated while using the service; Trackers.

Place of processing: Italy – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Contacting the User

Contact form (Blue Ocean Law Group)

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the User authorizes Blue Ocean Law Group to use these details

to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data processed: city; company name; country; email address; fax number; field of activity; first

name; last name; phone number; physical address; profession; state; various types of Data; website;

ZIP/Postal code.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; commercial information;

internet or other electronic network activity information; employment related information.

Mailing list or newsletter (Blue Ocean Law Group)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact

list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature

concerning Blue Ocean Law Group. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing

up to Blue Ocean Law Group or after making a purchase.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

Phone contact (Blue Ocean Law Group)

Users that provided their phone number might be contacted for commercial or promotional purposes related

to Blue Ocean Law Group, as well as for fulfilling support requests.

Personal Data processed: phone number.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

Content commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of Blue

Ocean Law Group.

Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an

email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of

comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.

If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for

the pages where the comment service is installed, even when Users do not use the content commenting

service.

Blog Comments

Users may add comments to blog posts (subject to moderator approval).

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)

The services contained in this section allow the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning

web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of Blue Ocean Law

Group.

Optimizely (Optimizely, Inc.)

Optimizely is an A/B testing service provided by Optimizely, Inc.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of Blue

Ocean Law Group and interact with them.

This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when

Users do not use it.

YouTube video widget (Google LLC)

YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google LLC that allows Blue Ocean Law Group

to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Handling activities related to productivity

This type of service helps the Owner to manage tasks, collaboration and, in general, activities related to

productivity. In using this type of service, Data of Users will be processed and may be retained, depending on

the purpose of the activity in question.

These services may be integrated with a wide range of third-party services disclosed within this privacy

policy to enable the Owner to import or export Data needed for the relative activity.

Jetboost (San Diego CA, USA)

Your No-Code Webflow Sidekick

On-page real-time search, dynamic filtering, and more for Webflow — without writing code

Used to enhance the user experience by enabling enhanced website search and filtering capabilities.

Your customers expect to be able to search your content. You've tried the native Webflow search, but you

want to search a single CMS list, not your entire site.

So, what if you could search items directly on your page, in real-time as you type?

Jetboost makes this possible, with instant, on-page search. It even works with paginated lists.

Jetboost Privacy Policy can be found here:

https://app.jetboost.io/privacy

Handling payments

Unless otherwise specified, Blue Ocean Law Group processes any payments by credit card, bank transfer or

other means via external payment service providers. In general and unless where otherwise stated, Users

are requested to provide their payment details and personal information directly to such payment service

providers. Blue Ocean Law Group isn't involved in the collection and processing of such information: instead,

it will only receive a notification by the relevant payment service provider as to whether payment has been

successfully completed.

PayPal (PayPal Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows Users to make online payments.

Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: See the PayPal privacy policy – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

Stripe (Stripe, Inc.)

Stripe is a payment service provided by Stripe, Inc.

Personal Data processed: billing address; first name; last name; payment info; various types of Data as

specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; commercial information.

Hosting and backend infrastructure

This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable Blue Ocean Law Group to run and

be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of Blue

Ocean Law Group.

Some services among those listed below, if any, may work through geographically distributed servers,

making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

Digital Safe Custody Vault (SOC 2 Type II Compliance)

Sign-Up to provide ongoing access to the Client's Digital Safe Custody Vault (provided as a white-labeled

service). SOC 2 Type II Compliance Attestation by Chartered Accountant.

Amazon Web Services (AWS) (Amazon Web Services, Inc.)

Amazon Web Services (AWS) is a hosting and backend service provided by Amazon Web Services, Inc.

Personal Data processed: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: Australia – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

Infrastructure monitoring

This type of service allows Blue Ocean Law Group to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its

performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these

services, whose function is to filter the activities of Blue Ocean Law Group.

Bugsnag (Bugsnag Inc.)

Bugsnag is a monitoring service provided by Bugsnag Inc.

Personal Data processed: Trackers.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the

pages of Blue Ocean Law Group.

The interaction and information obtained through Blue Ocean Law Group are always subject to the User’s

privacy settings for each social network.

This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when

Users do not use it.

It is recommended to log out from the respective services in order to make sure that the processed data on

Blue Ocean Law Group isn’t being connected back to the User’s profile.

Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (X Corp.)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network

provided by X Corp.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Interaction with live chat platforms

This type of service allows Users to interact with third-party live chat platforms directly from the pages of

Blue Ocean Law Group, in order to contact and be contacted by Blue Ocean Law Group‘s support service.

If one of these services is installed, it may collect browsing and Usage Data in the pages where it is installed,

even if the Users do not actively use the service. Moreover, live chat conversations may be logged.

WhatsApp Business Chat widget (Meta Platforms, Inc.)

WhatsApp Business Chat widget is a service for interacting with the WhatsApp instant messaging app and

platform provided by Meta Platforms, Inc.

Personal Data processed: answers to questions; contents of the email or message; Data communicated while

using the service; date of the message; first name; last name; phone number; profile picture; sender of the

message; time the message was sent; user content.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; internet or other electronic

network activity information; audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information; inferences

drawn from other personal information.

Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other

contact information to communicate with the User.

These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the

User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

BulkSMS (Blue Ocean Law Group)

BulkSMS is a phone numbers management and communication service provided by

\- Celerity Europe AG;

\- Celerity Systems Ltd;

\- Celerity Messaging Ltd.

Personal Data processed: phone number.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: various places depending on the company that provides the service – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

Mailchimp (Intuit Inc.)

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by Intuit Inc.

Personal Data processed: email address; first name.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers.

Operations

Cloud-based Legal Practice Management System (AU \& USA)

All data transmitted to our Cloud-based Legal Practice Management System is encrypted using SSL. Data is

encrypted at rest in both database and document-level storage.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Legal basis for data transfer: No data transfer.

Data retention period: 7 years.

Document Storage Systems (Australia \& US) with ISO/IEC 27001 Certification

Due to our CyberSecurity protocols, we can only divulge that we use secure Document Storage Systems.

When these systems are used the documents are stored on servers in Australia and the US. ISO/IEC 27001

Certification is the world’s best-known standard for information security management systems (ISMS) and

their requirements.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Data retention period: 7 years.

Platform services and hosting

These services have the purpose of hosting and running key components of Blue Ocean Law Group, therefore

allowing the provision of Blue Ocean Law Group from within a unified platform. Such platforms provide a

wide range of tools to the Owner – e.g. analytics, user registration, commenting, database management, e-

commerce, payment processing – that imply the collection and handling of Personal Data.

Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the

actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

Webflow (Webflow, Inc.)

Webflow is a platform provided by Webflow, Inc. that allows the Owner to build, run and host Blue Ocean Law

Group. Webflow is highly customizable and can host websites from simple blogs to complex e-commerce

platforms.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of

the service.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy – Opt out.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; internet or other electronic

network activity information.

Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow Blue Ocean Law Group to identify them and give them access to

dedicated services.

Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In

this case, Blue Ocean Law Group will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for

registration or identification purposes.

Some of the services listed below may also collect Personal Data for targeting and profiling purposes; to find

out more, please refer to the description of each service.

Trax Print

Protection For Documents And Identification Both Digital And Printed, using a unique closed-loop technology.

We also have the option to GPS-lock PDF documents so they can only be accessed by an authorized person

at the GPS location specified.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Selling goods and services online

This type of service helps the Owner to sell goods, provide services or monetize online content. To this end,

the services listed below may for instance allow the Owner to process payments, set up subscription models,

track orders, and manage deliveries.

Chargebee (Chargebee Inc.)

Chargebee is a subscription management tool provided by Chargebee Inc, which allows the Owner to

manage subscriptions, invoicing, pricing models, and subscription and revenue analytics.

Personal Data processed: Data communicated while using the service; Trackers; Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Selling goods and services online

White labelled LegalTech provider (Fluent Docs) of High-Quality Australian Legal Documents and Legal

Document Automation Software.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Spam and bots protection

This type of service analyzes the traffic of Blue Ocean Law Group, potentially containing Users' Personal

Data, with the purpose of filtering it from unwanted parts of traffic, messages and content that are

recognized as spam or protecting it from malicious bots activities.

Google reCAPTCHA (Google LLC)

Google reCAPTCHA is a SPAM protection service provided by Google LLC.

The use of reCAPTCHA is subject to the Google privacy policy and terms of use.

Personal Data processed: answers to questions; clicks; keypress events; motion sensor events; mouse

movements; scroll position; touch events; Trackers; Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information; inferences drawn from other personal information.

Tag Management

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on Blue Ocean Law Group in a

centralized fashion.

This results in the Users' Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this

Data.

Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.

Personal Data processed: Trackers; Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Traffic optimization and distribution

This type of service allows Blue Ocean Law Group to distribute their content using servers located across

different countries and to optimize their performance.

Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are

implemented. Their function is to filter communications between Blue Ocean Law Group and the User's

browser.

Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the

contents that may contain Personal Information of the User are transferred.

Cloudflare (Cloudflare, Inc.)

Cloudflare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by Cloudflare Inc.

The way Cloudflare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through Blue Ocean Law Group, i.e.,

communication between Blue Ocean Law Group and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data

from Blue Ocean Law Group to be collected.

Personal Data processed: Trackers.

Legal basis for processing: Consent.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: internet or other electronic network

activity information.

Amazon Cloudfront

Amazon Cloudfront is a Global Content Delivery Network (CDN) used to securely deliver content with low

latency and high transfer speeds.

Reach viewers across the globe in milliseconds with built-in data compression, edge compute capabilities,

and field-level encryption.

You can learn more here:

https://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/

You can find the Cloudfront Privacy Policy here:

https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/?nc1=f_pr

User database management

This type of service allows the Owner to build user profiles by starting from an email address, a personal

name, or other information that the User provides to Blue Ocean Law Group, as well as to track User

activities through analytics features. This Personal Data may also be matched with publicly available

information about the User (such as social networks' profiles) and used to build private profiles that the

Owner can display and use for improving Blue Ocean Law Group.

Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails based on

specific actions performed on Blue Ocean Law Group.

HubSpot CRM (HubSpot, Inc.)

HubSpot CRM is a User database management service provided by HubSpot, Inc.

Personal Data processed: email address; phone number; Trackers; various types of Data as specified in the

privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – Privacy Policy.

Category of personal information collected according to the CCPA: identifiers; internet or other electronic

network activity information.

Information on opting out of interest-based advertising

In addition to any opt-out feature provided by any of the services listed in this document, Users may learn

more on how to generally opt out of interest-based advertising within the dedicated section of the Cookie

Policy.

Further information about the processing of Personal Data

End-to-End Encrypted Email

Email Security and Compliance Standards are 100% compliant with HIPAA/HITECH, PII, GDPR, FSA, FINRA,

FERPA, CCPA.

Award-winning email security platform.

The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13

Users declare themselves to be adult according to their applicable legislation. Minors may use Blue Ocean

Law Group only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstance persons under the age of

13 may use Blue Ocean Law Group.

Cookie Policy

Blue Ocean Law Group uses Trackers. To learn more, Users may consult the Cookie Policy.

Further Information for Users

Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes.

provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-

contractual obligations thereof;

processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;

processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official

authority vested in the Owner;

processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third

party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in

particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement

necessary to enter into a contract.

Further information about retention time

Unless specified otherwise in this document, Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as

required by the purpose they have been collected for and may be retained for longer due to applicable legal

obligation or based on the Users’ consent.

Therefore:

Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and

the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.

Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as

needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests

pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent

to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to

retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to fulfil a legal obligation or upon order of an

authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right of access, the right to

erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the

retention period.

The rights of Users based on the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following, to the extent permitted by law:

Withdraw their consent at any time. Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have

previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.

Object to processing of their Data. Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if

the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent.

Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain

disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing

processing.

Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it

to be updated or corrected.

Restrict the processing of their Data. Users have the right to restrict the processing of their Data.

In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.

Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right to obtain the

erasure of their Data from the Owner.

Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller. Users have the right to receive

their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to

have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance.

Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection

authority.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis for Data transfers abroad including to any international

organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and

about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority

vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users

may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to

justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing

purposes, they can object to that processing at any time, free of charge and without providing

any justification. Where the User objects to processing for direct marketing purposes, the

Personal Data will no longer be processed for such purposes. To learn whether the Owner is

processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant

sections of this document.

How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in

this document. Such requests are free of charge and will be answered by the Owner as early as possible and

always within one month, providing Users with the information required by law. Any rectification or erasure

of Personal Data or restriction of processing will be communicated by the Owner to each recipient, if any, to

whom the Personal Data has been disclosed unless this proves impossible or involves disproportionate effort.

At the Users’ request, the Owner will inform them about those recipients.

Further information for Users in Brazil

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the entity running Blue Ocean Law Group and, if the case may be, its

parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”,

“our”).

This section applies to all Users in Brazil (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”),

according to the "Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados" (the "LGPD"), and for such Users, it supersedes any other

possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal information“ as it is defined in the LGPD.

The grounds on which we process your personal information

We can process your personal information solely if we have a legal basis for such processing. Legal bases are

as follows:

your consent to the relevant processing activities;

compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that lies with us;

the carrying out of public policies provided in laws or regulations or based on contracts, agreements and

similar legal instruments;

studies conducted by research entities, preferably carried out on anonymized personal information;

the carrying out of a contract and its preliminary procedures, in cases where you are a party to said

contract;

the exercising of our rights in judicial, administrative or arbitration procedures;

protection or physical safety of yourself or a third party;

the protection of health – in procedures carried out by health entities or professionals;

our legitimate interests, provided that your fundamental rights and liberties do not prevail over such

interests; and

credit protection.

To find out more about the legal bases, you can contact us at any time using the contact details provided in

this document.

Categories of personal information processed

To find out what categories of your personal information are processed, you can read the section titled

“Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.

Why we process your personal information

To find out why we process your personal information, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information

on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

Your Brazilian privacy rights, how to file a request and our response to your

requests

Your Brazilian privacy rights

You have the right to:

obtain confirmation of the existence of processing activities on your personal information;

access to your personal information;

have incomplete, inaccurate or outdated personal information rectified;

obtain the anonymization, blocking or elimination of your unnecessary or excessive personal

information, or of information that is not being processed in compliance with the LGPD;

obtain information on the possibility to provide or deny your consent and the consequences thereof;

obtain information about the third parties with whom we share your personal information;

obtain, upon your express request, the portability of your personal information (except for anonymized

information) to another service or product provider, provided that our commercial and industrial secrets

are safeguarded;

obtain the deletion of your personal information being processed if the processing was based upon your

consent, unless one or more exceptions provided for in art. 16 of the LGPD apply;

revoke your consent at any time;

lodge a complaint related to your personal information with the ANPD (the National Data Protection

Authority) or with consumer protection bodies;

oppose a processing activity in cases where the processing is not carried out in compliance with the

provisions of the law;

request clear and adequate information regarding the criteria and procedures used for an automated

decision; and

request the review of decisions made solely on the basis of the automated processing of your personal

information, which affect your interests. These include decisions to define your personal, professional,

consumer and credit profile, or aspects of your personality.

You will never be discriminated against, or otherwise suffer any sort of detriment, if you exercise your rights.

How to file your request

You can file your express request to exercise your rights free from any charge, at any time, by using the

contact details provided in this document, or via your legal representative.

How and when we will respond to your request

We will strive to promptly respond to your requests.

In any case, should it be impossible for us to do so, we’ll make sure to communicate to you the factual or

legal reasons that prevent us from immediately, or otherwise ever, complying with your requests. In cases

where we are not processing your personal information, we will indicate to you the physical or legal person to

whom you should address your requests, if we are in the position to do so.

In the event that you file an access or personal information processing confirmation request, please

make sure that you specify whether you’d like your personal information to be delivered in electronic or

printed form.

You will also need to let us know whether you want us to answer your request immediately, in which case we

will answer in a simplified fashion, or if you need a complete disclosure instead.

In the latter case, we’ll respond within 15 days from the time of your request, providing you with all the

information on the origin of your personal information, confirmation on whether or not records exist, any

criteria used for the processing and the purposes of the processing, while safeguarding our commercial and

industrial secrets.

In the event that you file a rectification, deletion, anonymization or personal information blocking

request, we will make sure to immediately communicate your request to other parties with whom we have

shared your personal information in order to enable such third parties to also comply with your request —

except in cases where such communication is proven impossible or involves disproportionate effort on our

side.

Transfer of personal information outside of Brazil permitted by the law

We are allowed to transfer your personal information outside of the Brazilian territory in the following cases:

when the transfer is necessary for international legal cooperation between public intelligence,

investigation and prosecution bodies, according to the legal means provided by the international law;

when the transfer is necessary to protect your life or physical security or those of a third party;

when the transfer is authorized by the ANPD;

when the transfer results from a commitment undertaken in an international cooperation agreement;

when the transfer is necessary for the execution of a public policy or legal attribution of public service;

when the transfer is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation, the carrying out of a

contract or preliminary procedures related to a contract, or the regular exercise of rights in judicial,

administrative or arbitration procedures.

Futher information for California consumers

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the business running Blue Ocean Law Group and, if the case may be, its

parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”,

“our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are

consumers residing in the state of California, United States of America, according to the "California

Consumer Privacy Act of 2018" (the "CCPA"), as updated by the "California Privacy Rights Act" (the "CPRA")

and subsequent regulations. For such consumers, this section supersedes any other possibly divergent or

conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the terms “personal information” (and “sensitive personal information”) as

defined in the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA).

Notice at collection

Categories of personal information collected, used, sold, or shared

In this section we summarize the categories of personal information that we've collected, used, sold, or

shared and the purposes thereof. You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled

“Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.

Information we collect: the categories of personal information we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal information about you: identifiers, commercial

information, internet or other electronic network activity information, audio, electronic, visual, thermal,

olfactory, or similar information, employment related information and inferences drawn from other personal

information.

We have collected the following categories of sensitive personal information: payment info and contents of

the email or message

We will not collect additional categories of personal information without notifying you.

Your right to limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information and how you can exercise it

You have the right to request that we limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information to

only that which is necessary to perform the services or provide the goods, as is reasonably expected by an

average consumer.

We can also use your sensitive personal information to perform specific purposes set forth by the law (such

as, including but not limited to, helping to ensure security and integrity; undertaking activities to verify or

maintain the quality or safety of our service) and as authorized by the relevant regulations.

Outside of the aforementioned specific purposes, you have the right to freely request, at any time, that we

do not use or disclose your sensitive personal information. This means that whenever you ask us to stop

using your sensitive personal information, we will abide by your request and we will instruct our service

providers and contractors to do the same.

To fully exercise your right to limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information you can

contact us at any time, using the contact details provided in this document.

For a simplified method you can also use the privacy choices link provided on Blue Ocean Law Group.

We use any personal information collected from you in connection with the submission of your request solely

for the purposes of complying with the request.

Once you have exercised this right, we are required to wait at least 12 months before asking whether you

have changed your mind.

What are the purposes for which we use your personal information?

We may use your personal information to allow the operational functioning of Blue Ocean Law Group and

features thereof (“business purposes”). In such cases, your personal information will be processed in a

fashion necessary and proportionate to the business purpose for which it was collected, and strictly within

the limits of compatible operational purposes.

We may also use your personal information for other reasons such as for commercial purposes (as indicated

within the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document), as well

as for complying with the law and defending our rights before the competent authorities where our rights

and interests are threatened or we suffer an actual damage.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes

originally disclosed, without your consent.

How long do we keep your personal information?

Unless stated otherwise inside the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section, we will

not retain your personal information for longer than is reasonably necessary for the purpose(s) they have

been collected for.

How we collect information: what are the sources of the personal information we collect?

We collect the above-mentioned categories of personal information, either directly or indirectly, from you

when you use Blue Ocean Law Group.

For example, you directly provide your personal information when you submit requests via any forms on Blue

Ocean Law Group. You also provide personal information indirectly when you navigate Blue Ocean Law

Group, as personal information about you is automatically observed and collected.

Finally, we may collect your personal information from third parties that work with us in connection with the

Service or with the functioning of this Application and features thereof.

How we use the information we collect: disclosing of your personal information with third parties for a business

purpose

For our purposes, the word “third party” means a person who is not any of the following: a service provider

or a contractor, as defined by the CCPA.

We disclose your personal information with the third parties listed in detail in the section titled

“Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document. These third

parties are grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

No sale of your personal information

We do not sell or share your personal information. In case we should decide to, we will inform you

beforehand and will grant your right to opt out of such sale.

What are the purposes for which we use your personal information?

We may use your personal information to allow the operational functioning of Blue Ocean Law Group and

features thereof (“business purposes”). In such cases, your personal information will be processed in a

fashion necessary and proportionate to the business purpose for which it was collected, and strictly within

the limits of compatible operational purposes.

We may also use your personal information for other reasons such as for commercial purposes (as indicated

within the section “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document), as well

as for complying with the law and defending our rights before the competent authorities where our rights

and interests are threatened or we suffer an actual damage.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes

originally disclosed, without your consent.

How long do we keep your personal information?

Unless stated otherwise inside the “Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” section, we will

not retain your personal information for longer than is reasonably necessary for the purpose(s) they have

been collected for.

Your privacy rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act and how to

exercise them

The right to access personal information: the right to know and to portability

You have the right to request that we disclose to you:

the categories of personal information that we collect about you;

the sources from which the personal information is collected;

the purposes for which we use your information;

to whom we disclose such information;

the specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.

You also have the right to know what personal information is sold or shared and to whom. In

particular, you have the right to request two separate lists from us where we disclose:

the categories of personal information that we sold or shared about you and the categories of third

parties to whom the personal information was sold or shared;

the categories of personal information that we disclosed about you for a business purpose and the

categories of persons to whom it was disclosed for a business purpose.

The disclosure described above will be limited to the personal information collected or used over the past 12

months.

If we deliver our response electronically, the information enclosed will be "portable", i.e. delivered in an

easily usable format to enable you to transmit the information to another entity without hindrance —

provided that this is technically feasible.

The right to request the deletion of your personal information

You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information, subject to exceptions set forth

by the law (such as, including but not limited to, where the information is used to identify and repair errors

on Blue Ocean Law Group, to detect security incidents and protect against fraudulent or illegal activities, to

exercise certain rights etc.).

If no legal exception applies, as a result of exercising your right, we will delete your personal information and

notify any of our service providers and all third parties to whom we have sold or shared the personal

information to do so — provided that this is technically feasible and doesn’t involve disproportionate effort.

The right to correct inaccurate personal information

You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal information we maintain about you,

taking into account the nature of the personal information and the purposes of the processing of the personal

information.

The right to opt out of sale or sharing of personal information and to limit the use of your

sensitive personal information

You have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your personal information. You also have the right to

request that we limit our use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information.

The right of no retaliation following opt-out or exercise of other rights (the right to non-

discrimination)

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. This means that we will not

discriminate against you, including, but not limited to, by denying goods or services, charging you a different

price, or providing a different level or quality of goods or services just because you exercised your consumer

privacy rights.

However, if you refuse to provide your personal information to us or ask us to delete or stop selling your

personal information, and that personal information or sale is necessary for us to provide you with goods or

services, we may not be able to complete that transaction.

To the extent permitted by the law, we may offer you promotions, discounts, and other deals in exchange for

collecting, keeping, or selling your personal information, provided that the financial incentive offered is

reasonably related to the value of your personal information.

How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your verifiable request to us by contacting us via

the details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, it’s necessary that we know who you are. Therefore, you can only exercise

the above rights by making a verifiable request which must:

provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we

collected personal information or an authorized representative;

describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond

to it.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity and therefore confirm the personal

information in our possession actually relates to you.

Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will use any

personal information collected from you in connection with the verification of your request solely for the

purposes of verification and shall not further disclose the personal information, retain it longer than

necessary for purposes of verification, or use it for unrelated purposes.

If you cannot personally submit a verifiable request, you can authorize a person registered with the California

Secretary of State to act on your behalf.

If you are an adult, you can make a verifiable request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

You can submit a maximum number of 2 requests over a period of 12 months.

How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will confirm receipt of your verifiable request within 10 days and provide information about how we will

process your request.

We will respond to your request within 45 days of its receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to

you the reasons why, and how much more time we need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to

90 days to fulfill your request.

Our disclosure(s) will cover the preceding 12-month period. Only with regard to personal information

collected on or after January 1, 2022, you have the right to request that we disclose information beyond the

12-month period, and we will provide them to you unless doing so proves impossible or would involve a

disproportionate effort.

Should we deny your request, we will explain you the reasons behind our denial.

We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable request unless such request is manifestly

unfounded or excessive. In such cases, we may charge a reasonable fee, or refuse to act on the request. In

either case, we will communicate our choices and explain the reasons behind it.

Further information for Virginia consumers

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the controller running this Application and, if the case may be, its parent,

subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”, “our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are

consumers residing in the Commonwealth of Virginia, according to the “Virginia Consumer Data Protection

Act" (the "VCDPA"), and, for such consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting

information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the VCDPA.

Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes

thereof. You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on

the processing of Persona Data” within this document.

Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, commercial information, internet

information, sensorial information, employment related information and inferred information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the

processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes

originally disclosed, without your consent.

You can freely give, deny, or withdraw such consent at any time using the contact details provided in this

document.

How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed

information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document. These third parties are

grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a natural or legal person, public authority, agency, or body

other than the consumer, controller, processor, or an affiliate of the processor or the controller" as defined by

the VCDPA.

Sale of your personal data

We do not sell your personal data. In case we should decide to, we will inform you beforehand and will grant

your right to opt out of such sale.

Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

We do not process your personal data for targeted advertising. If we decide to do so, we will inform you

beforehand and will grant your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted

advertising.

Your privacy rights under the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act and how to

exercise them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do

the following:

access personal data: the right to know. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or

not we are processing your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.

correct inaccurate personal data. You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate

personal data we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the

purposes of the processing of the personal data.

request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of

your personal data.

obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable

format that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity — provided that this is technically

feasible.

opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising , the

sale of personal data , or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly

significant effects concerning you.

non-discrimination. We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the VCDPA.

This means that we will not, among other things, deny goods or services, charge you a different price,

or provide a different level or quality of goods or services just because you exercised your consumer

privacy rights. However, if you refuse to provide your personal data to us or ask us to delete or stop

selling your personal data, and that personal data or sale is necessary for us to provide you with goods

or services, we may not be able to complete that transaction. To the extent permitted by the law, we

may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or services to you, including

offering goods or services for no fee, if you have exercised your right to opt out, or our offer is related to

your voluntary participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card

program.

How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the

contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable

efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases,

we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you

and your request.

Making a consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we may require you

to use your existing account. We will use any personal data collected from you in connection with your

request solely for the purposes of authentication, without further disclosing the personal data, retaining it

longer than necessary for purposes of authentication, or using it for unrelated purposes.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its

receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we

need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but

in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request. It is your right to appeal such decision

by submitting a request to us via the details provided in this document. Within 60 days of receipt of the

appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a

written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied you may contact the Attorney

General to submit a complaint.

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to two requests per year. If your request is

manifestly unfounded, excessive or repetitive, we may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to act on the

request. In either case, we will communicate our choices and explain the reasons behind them.

Further information for Colorado consumers

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the controller running Blue Ocean Law Group and, if the case may be, its

parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”,

“our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are

consumers residing in the State of Colorado, according to the “Colorado Privacy Act" (the "CPA"), and, for

such consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the

privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the CPA.

Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes

thereof. You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on

the processing of Persona Data” within this document.

Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, commercial information, internet

information, sensorial information, employment related information and inferred information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the

processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes

originally disclosed, without your consent.

You can freely give, deny, or withdraw such consent at any time using the contact details provided in this

document.

How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed

information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document. These third parties are

grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a person, public authority, agency, or body other than a

consumer, controller, processor, or affiliate of the processor or the controller." as defined by the CPA.

Sale of your personal data

We do not sell your personal data. In case we should decide to, we will inform you beforehand and will grant

your right to opt out of such sale.

For our purposes, the word "sale", "sell", or "sold" means "the exchange of personal data for monetary or

other valuable consideration by a controller to a third party" as defined by the CPA.

Please note that according to the CPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes personal

data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set forth in the

CPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for the provision of

a product or service requested by you.

Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

We do not process your personal data for targeted advertising. If we decide to do so, we will inform you

beforehand and will grant your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted

advertising.

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying to a consumer an advertisement that is

selected based on personal data obtained or inferred over time from the consumer's activities across

nonaffiliated websites, applications, or online services to predict consumer preferences or interests" as

defined by CPA.

Please note that according to the CPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements directed to a

consumer in response to the consumer's request for information or feedback; advertisements based on

activities within a controller's own websites or online applications or any affiliated website or online

application; advertisements based on the context of a consumer's current search query, visit to an internet

web site or online application; or processing personal data solely to measure or report advertising frequency,

performance or reach”.

Your privacy rights under the Colorado Privacy Act and how to exercise them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do

the following:

opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of

personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects

concerning you.

access personal data. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing

your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.

correct inaccurate personal data. You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal

data we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the purposes of

the processing of the personal data.

request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of your

personal data.

obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format

that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity – provided that this is technically feasible.

In any case, we will not increase the cost of, or decrease the availability of, a product or service, based solely

on the exercise of any of your rights and unrelated to the feasibility or the value of a service. However, to the

extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or

services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if our offer is related to your voluntary

participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the

contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are and which right you wish to exercise.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable

efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases,

we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you

and your request.

Making a consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we may require you

to use your existing account. We will use any personal data collected from you in connection with your

request solely for the purposes of authentication, without further disclosing the personal data, retaining it

longer than necessary for purposes of authentication, or using it for unrelated purposes.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its

receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we

need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but

in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request. It is your right to appeal such decision

by submitting a request to us via the details provided in this document. Within 45 days of receipt of the

appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a

written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied you may contact the Attorney

General to submit a complaint.

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to two requests per year.

Further information for Connecticut consumers

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the controller running Blue Ocean Law Group and, if the case may be, its

parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”,

“our”).

This section applies o all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are

consumers residing in the State of Connecticut, according to “An Act Concerning Personal Data Privacy and

Online Monitoring " (also known as "The Connecticut Data Privacy Act" or the “CTDPA"), and, for such

consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy

policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the CTDPA.

Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes

thereof. You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on

the processing of Persona Data” within this document.

Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, commercial information, internet

information, sensorial information, employment related information and inferred information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the

processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

We won’t process your information for unexpected purposes, or for purposes incompatible with the purposes

originally disclosed, without your consent.

You can freely give, deny, or withdraw such consent at any time using the contact details provided in this

document.

How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed

information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document. These third parties are

grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a person, public authority, agency, or body other than a

consumer, controller, processor, or affiliate of the processor or the controller." as defined by the CTDPA.

Sale of your personal data

We do not sell your personal data. In case we should decide to, we will inform you beforehand and will grant

your right to opt out of such sale.

For our purposes, the word "sale", "sell", or "sold" means "the exchange of personal data for monetary or

other valuable consideration by a controller to a third party" as defined by the CTDPA.

Please note that according to the CTDPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes

personal data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set

forth in the CTDPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for

the provision of a product or service requested by you.

Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

We do not process your personal data for targeted advertising. If we decide to do so, we will inform you

beforehand and will grant your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted

advertising.

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying to a consumer an advertisement that is

selected based on personal data obtained or inferred over time from the consumer's activities across non

affiliated websites, applications, or online services to predict consumer preferences or interests" as defined

by CTDPA.

Please note that according to the CTDPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements based on

activities within a controller's own web sites or online applications; advertisements based on the context of a

consumer's current search query, visit to an internet web site or online application; advertisements directed

to a consumer in response to the consumer's request for information or feedback; or processing personal

data solely to measure or report advertising frequency, performance or reach”.

Your privacy rights under the Connecticut Data Privacy Act and how to exercise

them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do

the following:

access personal data. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing

your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.

correct inaccurate personal data. You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate personal

data we maintain about you, taking into account the nature of the personal data and the purposes of

the processing of the personal data.

request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of your

personal data.

obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format

that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity – provided that this is technically feasible.

opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of

personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects

concerning you.

In any case, we will not increase the cost of, or decrease the availability of, a product or service, based solely

on the exercise of any of your rights and unrelated to the feasibility or the value of a service. However, to the

extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or

services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if our offer is related to your voluntary

participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the

contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are and which right you wish to exercise.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable

efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases,

we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you

and your request.

Making a consumer request does not require you to create an account with us. However, we may require you

to use your existing account. We will use any personal data collected from you in connection with your

request solely for the purposes of authentication, without further disclosing the personal data, retaining it

longer than necessary for purposes of authentication, or using it for unrelated purposes.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its

receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we

need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but

in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request. It is your right to appeal such decision

by submitting a request to us via the details provided in this document. Within 45 days of receipt of the

appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a

written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied, you may contact the Attorney

General to submit a complaint.

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to one request per year.

Further information for Utah consumers

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the controller running Blue Ocean Law Group and, if the case may be, its

parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”,

“our”).

This section applies to all Users (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”), who are

consumers residing in the State of Utah, according to the “Consumer Privacy Act" (the “UCPA"), and, for such

consumers, it supersedes any other possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy

policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal data” as defined in the UCPA.

Categories of personal data processed

In this section, we summarize the categories of personal data that we've processed and the purposes

thereof. You can read about these activities in detail in the section titled “Detailed information on

the processing of Persona Data” within this document.

Categories of personal data we collect

We have collected the following categories of personal data: identifiers, commercial information, internet

information, sensorial information, employment related information and inferred information

We do not collect sensitive data.

We will not collect additional categories of personal data without notifying you.

Why we process your personal data

To find out why we process your personal data, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information on the

processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

How we use the data we collect: sharing of your personal data with third parties

We share your personal data with the third parties listed in detail in the section titled “Detailed

information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document. These third parties are

grouped and categorized in accordance with the different purposes of processing.

For our purposes, the word "third party" means "a person other than: the consumer, controller, or processor;

or an affiliate or contractor of the controller or the processor" as defined by the UCPA.

Sale of your personal data

We do not sell your personal data. In case we should decide to, we will inform you beforehand and will grant

your right to opt out of such sale.

For our purposes, the word "sale", "sell", or "sold" means "the exchange of personal data for monetary or

other valuable consideration by a controller to a third party" as defined by the UCPA.

Please note that according to the UCPA, the disclosure of personal data to a processor that processes

personal data on behalf of a controller does not constitute a sale. In addition, other specific exceptions set

forth in the UCPA may apply, such as, but not limited to, the disclosure of personal data to a third party for

the provision of a product or service requested by you.

Processing of your personal data for targeted advertising

We do not process your personal data for targeted advertising. If we decide to do so, we will inform you

beforehand and will grant your right to opt out of the processing of your personal data for targeted

advertising.

For our purposes, the word "targeted advertising" means "displaying to a consumer an advertisement that is

selected based on personal data obtained or inferred over time from the consumer's activities across

nonaffiliated websites, applications, or online services to predict consumer preferences or interests" as

defined by UCPA.

Please note that according to the UCPA, targeted advertising does not include: “advertisements based on

activities within a controller's own websites or online applications or any affiliated website or online

application; advertisements based on the context of a consumer's current search query, visit to an web site

or online application; advertisements directed to a consumer in response to the consumer's request for

information, product, a service or feedback; or processing personal data solely to measure or report

advertising performance, reach or frequency.”

Your privacy rights under the Utah Consumer Privacy Act and how to exercise

them

You may exercise certain rights regarding your data processed by us. In particular, you have the right to do

the following:

access personal data. You have the right to request that we confirm whether or not we are processing

your personal data. You also have the right to access such personal data.

request the deletion of your personal data. You have the right to request that we delete any of your

personal data.

obtain a copy of your personal data. We will provide your personal data in a portable and usable format

that allows you to transfer data easily to another entity – provided that this is technically feasible.

opt out of the processing of your personal data for the purposes of targeted advertising or the sale of

personal data.

In any case, we will not increase the cost of, or decrease the availability of, a product or service, based solely

on the exercise of any of your rights and unrelated to the feasibility or the value of a service. However, to the

extent permitted by the law, we may offer a different price, rate, level, quality, or selection of goods or

services to you, including offering goods or services for no fee, if our offer is related to your voluntary

participation in a bona fide loyalty, rewards, premium features, discounts, or club card program.

How to exercise your rights

To exercise the rights described above, you need to submit your request to us by contacting us via the

contact details provided in this document.

For us to respond to your request, we need to know who you are and which right you wish to exercise.

We will not respond to any request if we are unable to verify your identity using commercially reasonable

efforts and therefore confirm that the personal data in our possession actually relate to you. In such cases,

we may request that you provide additional information which is reasonably necessary to authenticate you

and your request. We may retain your email address to respond to your request.

If you are an adult, you can make a request on behalf of a child under your parental authority.

How and when we are expected to handle your request

We will respond to your request without undue delay, but in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of its

receipt. Should we need more time, we will explain to you the reasons why, and how much more time we

need. In this regard, please note that we may take up to 90 days to fulfill your request.

Should we deny your request, we will explain to you the reasons behind our denial without undue delay, but

in all cases and at the latest within 45 days of receipt of the request.

We do not charge a fee to respond to your request, for up to one request per year.

Additional information about Data collection and processing

Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to

possible legal action arising from improper use of Blue Ocean Law Group or the related Services.

The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of

public authorities.

Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, Blue Ocean Law Group may provide the User

with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of

Personal Data upon request.

System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, Blue Ocean Law Group and any third-party services may collect

files that record interaction with Blue Ocean Law Group (System logs) or use other Personal Data (such as

the IP Address) for this purpose.

Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at

any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by notifying its Users on this

page and possibly within Blue Ocean Law Group and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a

notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this

page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall

collect new consent from the User, where required.

Further information for Users in Brazil

This section of the document integrates with and supplements the information contained in the rest of the

privacy policy and is provided by the entity running Blue Ocean Law Group and, if the case may be, its

parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (for the purposes of this section referred to collectively as “we”, “us”,

“our”).

This section applies to all Users in Brazil (Users are referred to below, simply as “you”, “your”, “yours”),

according to the "Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados" (the "LGPD"), and for such Users, it supersedes any other

possibly divergent or conflicting information contained in the privacy policy.

This part of the document uses the term “personal information“ as it is defined in the LGPD.

The grounds on which we process your personal information

We can process your personal information solely if we have a legal basis for such processing. Legal bases are

as follows:

your consent to the relevant processing activities;

compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that lies with us;

the carrying out of public policies provided in laws or regulations or based on contracts, agreements and

similar legal instruments;

studies conducted by research entities, preferably carried out on anonymized personal information;

the carrying out of a contract and its preliminary procedures, in cases where you are a party to said

contract;

the exercising of our rights in judicial, administrative or arbitration procedures;

protection or physical safety of yourself or a third party;

the protection of health – in procedures carried out by health entities or professionals;

our legitimate interests, provided that your fundamental rights and liberties do not prevail over such

interests; and

credit protection.

To find out more about the legal bases, you can contact us at any time using the contact details provided in

this document.

Categories of personal information processed

To find out what categories of your personal information are processed, you can read the section titled

“Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data” within this document.

Why we process your personal information

To find out why we process your personal information, you can read the sections titled “Detailed information

on the processing of Personal Data” and “The purposes of processing” within this document.

Your Brazilian privacy rights, how to file a request and our response to your

requests

Your Brazilian privacy rights

You have the right to:

obtain confirmation of the existence of processing activities on your personal information;

access to your personal information;

have incomplete, inaccurate or outdated personal information rectified;

obtain the anonymization, blocking or elimination of your unnecessary or excessive personal

information, or of information that is not being processed in compliance with the LGPD;

obtain information on the possibility to provide or deny your consent and the consequences thereof;

obtain information about the third parties with whom we share your personal information;

obtain, upon your express request, the portability of your personal information (except for anonymized

information) to another service or product provider, provided that our commercial and industrial secrets

are safeguarded;

obtain the deletion of your personal information being processed if the processing was based upon your

consent, unless one or more exceptions provided for in art. 16 of the LGPD apply;

revoke your consent at any time;

lodge a complaint related to your personal information with the ANPD (the National Data Protection

Authority) or with consumer protection bodies;

oppose a processing activity in cases where the processing is not carried out in compliance with the

provisions of the law;

request clear and adequate information regarding the criteria and procedures used for an automated

decision; and

request the review of decisions made solely on the basis of the automated processing of your personal

information, which affect your interests. These include decisions to define your personal, professional,

consumer and credit profile, or aspects of your personality.

You will never be discriminated against, or otherwise suffer any sort of detriment, if you exercise your rights.

How to file your request

You can file your express request to exercise your rights free from any charge, at any time, by using the

contact details provided in this document, or via your legal representative.

How and when we will respond to your request

We will strive to promptly respond to your requests.

In any case, should it be impossible for us to do so, we’ll make sure to communicate to you the factual or

legal reasons that prevent us from immediately, or otherwise ever, complying with your requests. In cases

where we are not processing your personal information, we will indicate to you the physical or legal person to

whom you should address your requests, if we are in the position to do so.

In the event that you file an access or personal information processing confirmation request, please

make sure that you specify whether you’d like your personal information to be delivered in electronic or

printed form.

You will also need to let us know whether you want us to answer your request immediately, in which case we

will answer in a simplified fashion, or if you need a complete disclosure instead.

In the latter case, we’ll respond within 15 days from the time of your request, providing you with all the

information on the origin of your personal information, confirmation on whether or not records exist, any

criteria used for the processing and the purposes of the processing, while safeguarding our commercial and

industrial secrets.

In the event that you file a rectification, deletion, anonymization or personal information blocking

request, we will make sure to immediately communicate your request to other parties with whom we have

shared your personal information in order to enable such third parties to also comply with your request —

except in cases where such communication is proven impossible or involves disproportionate effort on our

side.

Transfer of personal information outside of Brazil permitted by the law

We are allowed to transfer your personal information outside of the Brazilian territory in the following cases:

when the transfer is necessary for international legal cooperation between public intelligence,

investigation and prosecution bodies, according to the legal means provided by the international law;

when the transfer is necessary to protect your life or physical security or those of a third party;

when the transfer is authorized by the ANPD;

when the transfer results from a commitment undertaken in an international cooperation agreement;

when the transfer is necessary for the execution of a public policy or legal attribution of public service;

when the transfer is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation, the carrying out of a

contract or preliminary procedures related to a contract, or the regular exercise of rights in judicial,

administrative or arbitration procedures.

Definitions and legal references

Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal

identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

Usage Data

Information collected automatically through Blue Ocean Law Group (or third-party services employed in Blue

Ocean Law Group), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the

Users who use Blue Ocean Law Group, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the

request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the

numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of

origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per

visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within

the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the

device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

User

The individual using Blue Ocean Law Group who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

Data Processor (or Processor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf

of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others,

determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures

concerning the operation and use of Blue Ocean Law Group. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified,

is the Owner of Blue Ocean Law Group.

Blue Ocean Law Group (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

Service

The service provided by Blue Ocean Law Group as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this

site/application.

European Union (or EU)

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all

current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area.

Cookie

Cookies are Trackers consisting of small sets of data stored in the User's browser.

Tracker

Tracker indicates any technology - e.g Cookies, unique identifiers, web beacons, embedded scripts, e-tags

and fingerprinting - that enables the tracking of Users, for example by accessing or storing information on

the User’s device.

Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations.

This privacy policy relates solely to Blue Ocean Law Group, if not stated otherwise within this document.

Latest update: October 05, 2023
